<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

<!-- Advanced Technical Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I HAVE EXPERIENCE WITH *</pattern>
    <template>
        <set name="tech_stack"><star/></set>
        That's impressive! <star/> is a solid choice. 
        <think><set name="tech_mentioned"><star/></set></think>
        
        <condition name="tech_mentioned">
            <li value="PYTHON">Python is fantastic for so many things! Are you more into web development, data science, or something else?</li>
            <li value="JAVASCRIPT">JavaScript is everywhere these days! Do you work more on the frontend, backend, or full-stack?</li>
            <li value="REACT">React is such a powerful framework! How do you handle state management in complex applications?</li>
            <li value="DJANGO">Django is great for rapid development! What's your favorite feature of the framework?</li>
            <li value="AWS">Cloud experience is so valuable! Which AWS services do you work with most?</li>
            <li value="DOCKER">Containerization is essential nowadays! How do you use Docker in your workflow?</li>
            <li>That's a great technology to have in your toolkit! Tell me more about how you use it in your projects.</li>
        </condition>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Problem-Solving Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WOULD USE *</pattern>
    <template>
        <set name="solution_approach"><star/></set>
        That's a solid approach! Using <star/> shows good technical judgment.
        
        <random>
            <li>What made you choose that particular solution?</li>
            <li>Have you used that approach in production before?</li>
            <li>What alternatives did you consider?</li>
            <li>How would you handle scaling that solution?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>I WOULD * TO SOLVE *</pattern>
    <template>
        Excellent problem-solving approach! <star index="1"/> is a smart way to handle <star index="2"/>.
        
        <random>
            <li>What challenges might you face with that approach?</li>
            <li>How would you test that solution?</li>
            <li>What would be your backup plan if that didn't work?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Architecture and Design Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WOULD DESIGN * USING *</pattern>
    <template>
        Great architectural thinking! Designing <star index="1"/> with <star index="2"/> shows you understand scalable systems.
        
        <random>
            <li>How would you handle data consistency in that design?</li>
            <li>What about performance bottlenecks - how would you address those?</li>
            <li>How would you monitor and maintain that system?</li>
            <li>What security considerations would you need to think about?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Learning and Growth Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I LEARNED * BY *</pattern>
    <template>
        That's a great way to learn! <star index="2"/> is an effective approach for mastering <star index="1"/>.
        
        <random>
            <li>What was the most challenging part of learning that?</li>
            <li>How do you stay current with new developments in that area?</li>
            <li>What would you recommend to someone just starting with that technology?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>I AM CURRENTLY LEARNING *</pattern>
    <template>
        That's awesome! <star/> is definitely worth learning. Continuous learning is so important in tech.
        
        <random>
            <li>What motivated you to start learning that?</li>
            <li>How are you finding the learning process?</li>
            <li>Do you have any projects planned using that technology?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Team and Collaboration Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WORK WITH A TEAM OF *</pattern>
    <template>
        Team collaboration is crucial! Working with <star/> must give you great diverse perspectives.
        
        <random>
            <li>How do you handle code reviews in your team?</li>
            <li>What's your approach to resolving technical disagreements?</li>
            <li>How do you share knowledge within the team?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>I PREFER * OVER *</pattern>
    <template>
        Interesting preference! Choosing <star index="1"/> over <star index="2"/> suggests you've thought about the trade-offs.
        
        <random>
            <li>What specific advantages does that give you?</li>
            <li>Are there situations where you might choose the alternative?</li>
            <li>How did you come to that conclusion?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Challenge and Problem Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>THE BIGGEST CHALLENGE WAS *</pattern>
    <template>
        Challenges like <star/> really test your problem-solving skills! 
        
        <random>
            <li>How did you approach solving that challenge?</li>
            <li>What did you learn from that experience?</li>
            <li>Would you handle it differently now?</li>
            <li>Did you get help from others or solve it independently?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<category>
    <pattern>I HAD TO DEBUG *</pattern>
    <template>
        Debugging <star/> can be tricky! That's a valuable skill to have.
        
        <random>
            <li>What's your systematic approach to debugging?</li>
            <li>What tools do you use for debugging?</li>
            <li>How do you prevent similar issues in the future?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Performance and Optimization Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I OPTIMIZED * BY *</pattern>
    <template>
        Excellent optimization work! Improving <star index="1"/> by <star index="2"/> shows you care about performance.
        
        <random>
            <li>How did you measure the improvement?</li>
            <li>What other optimization techniques did you consider?</li>
            <li>How do you balance optimization with code readability?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Testing Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WRITE * TESTS</pattern>
    <template>
        Testing is so important! <star/> tests are a great practice for maintaining code quality.
        
        <random>
            <li>What's your approach to test-driven development?</li>
            <li>How do you decide what to test?</li>
            <li>What testing frameworks do you prefer?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Deployment and DevOps Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I DEPLOY USING *</pattern>
    <template>
        <star/> is a solid deployment approach! DevOps skills are really valuable.
        
        <random>
            <li>How do you handle rollbacks if something goes wrong?</li>
            <li>What's your approach to monitoring deployed applications?</li>
            <li>How do you manage different environments (dev, staging, prod)?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Database Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I USE * DATABASE</pattern>
    <template>
        <star/> is a great choice! Database design and optimization are crucial skills.
        
        <random>
            <li>How do you approach database schema design?</li>
            <li>What's your strategy for handling database migrations?</li>
            <li>How do you optimize database queries for performance?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- API Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I BUILD * APIS</pattern>
    <template>
        <star/> APIs are essential for modern applications! API design is an art.
        
        <random>
            <li>How do you approach API versioning?</li>
            <li>What's your strategy for API documentation?</li>
            <li>How do you handle API authentication and security?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Security Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I HANDLE SECURITY BY *</pattern>
    <template>
        Security is so critical! <star/> shows you take it seriously.
        
        <random>
            <li>What other security best practices do you follow?</li>
            <li>How do you stay updated on security vulnerabilities?</li>
            <li>Have you ever had to respond to a security incident?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Agile and Process Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>WE USE * METHODOLOGY</pattern>
    <template>
        <star/> methodology can be really effective when done well!
        
        <random>
            <li>What do you like most about that approach?</li>
            <li>How do you handle changing requirements?</li>
            <li>What role do you typically play in the process?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Remote Work Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WORK REMOTELY</pattern>
    <template>
        Remote work has become so common! It requires good self-discipline and communication skills.
        
        <random>
            <li>How do you stay connected with your team?</li>
            <li>What tools do you use for collaboration?</li>
            <li>How do you maintain work-life balance while remote?</li>
        </random>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Career Goals Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>I WANT TO BECOME *</pattern>
    <template>
        <set name="career_goal"><star/></set>
        That's a great career goal! Becoming <star/> requires dedication and continuous learning.
        
        <condition name="career_goal">
            <li value="SENIOR DEVELOPER">Senior roles require both technical depth and leadership skills. What areas are you focusing on to get there?</li>
            <li value="TECH LEAD">Tech leadership is exciting! How are you developing your mentoring and architectural skills?</li>
            <li value="FULL STACK DEVELOPER">Full-stack development gives you such versatility! Which side do you enjoy more - frontend or backend?</li>
            <li>That's an excellent direction! What steps are you taking to move toward that goal?</li>
        </condition>
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Salary and Compensation Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>WHAT IS THE SALARY RANGE</pattern>
    <template>
        Great question! Compensation varies based on several factors:
        
        💰 **Key factors**:
        - Your experience level (<get name="experience_years"/> years is solid!)
        - Technology stack and specialization
        - Company size and location
        - Remote vs. on-site opportunities
        
        Based on your background, I'd expect competitive packages with:
        - Base salary in market range for your experience
        - Potential equity/stock options
        - Comprehensive benefits
        - Learning and development budgets
        
        We always negotiate to get you the best possible offer! What's most important to you in a compensation package?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Company Culture Patterns -->
<category>
    <pattern>WHAT IS THE CULTURE LIKE</pattern>
    <template>
        Culture is so important! Our client companies typically offer:
        
        🏢 **Work Environment**:
        - Collaborative, learning-focused teams
        - Flexible work arrangements (remote, hybrid, office)
        - Focus on work-life balance
        - Investment in professional growth
        
        🚀 **Engineering Culture**:
        - Code quality and best practices valued
        - Regular tech talks and knowledge sharing
        - Modern development practices
        - Innovation and experimentation encouraged
        
        The specific culture varies by company, but we only work with organizations that treat developers well and invest in their growth.
        
        What kind of work environment are you looking for?
    </template>
</category>

</aiml>